Register of the American Relief Administration Russian operational records
Hoover Institution Archives
American Relief Administration Russian operational records
1919-1925
23003
Hoover Institution Archives
555 manuscript boxes, 2 cubic foot boxes, 5 oversize boxes (236.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, telegrams, memoranda, reports, agreements, minutes, histories, financial records, lists, press summaries, and photographs relating to American relief in the Soviet Union following the Russian Civil War, and food and public health problems, agriculture, economic conditions, transportation and communications, and political and social developments, in the Soviet Union.
American Relief Administration.
Litvinov, M. M. (Maksim Maksimovich), 1876-1951.
Nansen, Fridtjof, 1861-1930.
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.
Gorky, Maksim, 1868-1936.
American Friends Service Committee.
American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee.
American Mennonite Central Committee.
American National Red Cross.
National Lutheran Council.
Near East Relief (Organization)
Save the Children Fund (Great Britain).
United States Grain Corporation.
United States. Navy.
Access
Microfilm use only, except for boxes 395-411 and 560-562.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1923.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (664 reels).
Historical Note
The American Relief Administration was established in February 1919 as the agency designated by President Woodrow Wilson to administer the relief measures authorized by the Congressional appropriation of $100,000,000 approved February 25, 1919. During the period of its activity, 1919-1923, offices of the A.R.A. were established in New York, Washington, and major cities of Europe, the Near East, and Soviet Russia. Russian relief was initiated in August 1921 under an agreement with the Soviet government, and by 1923 district missions were established in the capitals of most of the provinces of the Russian Socialist Federated Soviet Republic, the Ukraine, the Crimea, and the North Caucasus.
In total, the A.R.A. furnished over 90 percent of all relief that went into Russian between 1921 and 1923. Soviet authorities provided all transportation, warehousing, buildings, and currency required for payment of Russian staff. Funds equalling some $60,000,000 were made available by Congressional appropriation, public charity, and Soviet government gold reserves. Administrative personnel numbered 200 Americans with about 80,000 Russians under their direction. Between 1921 and 1923, a little under a million tons of food, seed, clothing, and medical supplies were distributed in Russia through an organization of 35,000 different stations. During the worst period nearly 11,000,000 men, women, and children were fed. Medical supplies were furnished to 15,000 hospitals and institutions, and over 7,000,000 individuals received inoculations and vaccinations. From seed imported, about 8,000,000 acres of land were sown.
During the Russian operations principal officers of the A.R.A. included Herbert Hoover, Chairman; William N. Haskell, Director for Russia; Cyril J. C. Quinn, Assistant Director for Russia; Henry Beeuwkes, Medical Director for Russia; Vernon Kellogg, Lincoln Hutchinson, and James P. Goodrich, Special Investigators for Russia; Frank A. Golder, Special Representative, Russia;Edmund L. Daley and Philip Mathews, Executive Assistants for Russia; Walter Lyman Brown, Director for Europe; Christian A. Herter, Assistant Director,Washington Office; James A. Logan, Jr., Continental Representative, Paris Office; Philip S. Baldwin, Chief, Poland and Danzig Office; Randolph C. Wilson,Chief, Hamburg Office; and Arthur C. Ringland, Chief, Constantinople Office.
A.R.A. operations terminated in Russia on June 15, 1923.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, telegrams, memoranda, reports, agreements, minutes, histories, financial records, lists, press summaries, and photographs relating to American relief in the Soviet Union following the Russian Civil War, and food and public health problems, agriculture, economic conditions, transportation and communications, and political and social developments, in the Soviet Union.
Appendix A: Partial List of Districts and Towns Served by the A.R.A.
Crimean District - Feodosia
Atouzi
Einlage
Erapokino
Feodosia
Sevastopol
Simferopol
Zinevko
Kazan District - Tartar Republic
Kazan
Minsk District
Minsk
Moscow District
Moscow
Petrograd District
Petrograd
Samara District - Bugurus Uzed
Buzuluk
Orenburg
Samara
Stavropol
Saratov District
Saratov
Simbirsk District
Simbirsk
Tsaritsyn District - The Don Cossacks
Spaask
Tsaritsyn
Ufa District - The Bashkir Republic
Chelyabinsk
Chouganack
Ekaterinburg
Miass, Siberia
Ufa
Sterlitimak
Zlaroust
Ukraine District - Odessa
Alexandrovsk
Belgorod
Choutitsa
Ekaterinoslav
Kharkov
Kiev
Mariupol
Melitopol
Nikolaev
Odessa
Poltava
Appendix B: Partial List of American Personnel Pictured in Personnel Photographs
The Crimea
Brown, J. M.
Kohl, Tracy
Morehead, Dr.
Kazan
Boyd, J. H.
Cox, J. E., Dr.
Turner
Venear, S.
Petrograd, Moscow, and Minsk
Beeuwkes, Henry, Dr.
Blattman, B.
Brown, Walter Lyman
Burland, Elmer
Carroll, Philip J.
Davenport, Walter P., Dr.
Dawson, J. H.
Gilchrist, Harry L.
Golder, Frank A.
Goodrich, Governor
Grove, C. W., Lt.
Haskell, Billy (son of William N. Haskell)
Haskell, Henry, Dr.
Haskell, William N., Col.
Hutchinson, Lincoln
Johnson, Charles H.
Kellogg, Vernon
Mangan, J. J.
Mitchel, M. M.
Nickelson, Dr.
Pate, Maurice
Quinn, C. J.
Rickard, Edgar
Ringland, Arthur
Robbins, Caroline
Shafroth, William C.
Walker, Herschel C.
Samara
Foucar, F., Dr.
Wolfe, Henry
Saratov
Cobb, Russel
Hand
Kinne, David
Stack, J., Dr.
Simbirsk
Coleman
Dawson, J. H.
Fox, Edward
Godfrey, M., Dr.
Levit, Dr.
Rein, Richard
Renshaw, Evan
Sheild, Philip B.
Tsaritsyn
Bowden, Carlton
Cormick, George, Dr.
Morris, C. S.
Stephens, Dorsey
Ufa
Beard, Bernard
Bell, William, Col.
Blandy, Harold
Dickinson, Dr.
Garner, W. C.
Hofstra, Piet Hein
Kelly, W. F.
Krueger, J. W., Col.
Lykes, Gibbes
Rollins, Dr.
Sloan, Dr.
The Ukraine
Harrington, George
Hynes, J. H.
Lyman, Frank, Dr.
Meyer, Rev.
Morehead, Dr.
Parker, Leonidas
Spratt, J. W.
Miscellaneous
Baird, S. P.
Daley
Dickinson, T. H.
Dodge, Earl
Flesh, E. M.
Gardner, Nellie E.
Janicki, J. M.
Lonergan, J. M.
Pearson, R. A.
Rapp, George
Renshaw, Donald
Smith, C. C.
Telford, Major
Traynham, Floyd
Wood, Lt.
Appendix C: Partial List of Russian Officials and Citizens Who Worked fro the A.R.A., Pictured in Personnel and Other Photographs
Ablitsov (Ablitzoff)
Akmidulin, Fachii (Fachy Acmidoulin)
Alekseev (Alexef)
Babin, Aleksei (Alexis Babine)
Borodin, B. G.
Butkovskii (Butkowski)
Chakuntkhakova, Mrs. (Mrs. Tchakounthakoff)
Chernik (Tchernik)
Chicherin (Tchtcherin)
Eiduk, Aleksandr (Alexander Eiduk)
Elmanov (Elmanoff)
Gerstnovich, Lev (Leon Gerstnovich)
Iakunchipov, Olga (Olga Yacountchipoff)
Kamenev, Lev (Leon Kamenev)
Kameneva, Mrs.
Krasin (Krassin)
Kubalerova, Mariia
Lander
Litvinov, Maksim (Maxime Litvinoff)
Nikolaev, Dr. (Dr. Nickelaev)
Popov, Iurii (Georges Poppoff)
Radek
Sabin, Kyra (Kyra Sabine)
Savalev (Savalieff)
Semiashko
Shukov, Z. Z. (Z. Z. Shukoff)
Simonov, Dr. (Dr. Simonoff)
Tregubov, S., Dr. (Dr. S. Tregubow)
Trotsky, Leon
Trotsky, Natalia Sedova (Mrs. Leon Trotsky)
Volodin, A. S. (A. S. Volodjin)
Zhukov (Zhukoff)
Zinovyev, Grigory Yevseyevich (Tovarisch, Zenovieff)
Zubarev (Zoubareff)
Child welfare--Soviet Union.; International relief.; Prisoners of war.; Reconstruction (1914-1939)--Soviet Union.; Refugees.; Transportation--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Economic conditions--1917-1945.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Civilian relief.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Refugees.; Young Men's Christian associations.; Young Women's Christian associations.
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Other Finding Aids
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- Original Acquisition
- New York Office, Subject File, 1919-1924
  General note
  Available on microfilm reels 1-193
  Scope and Contents note
  Reports, memoranda, correspondence, agreements, minutes of meetings, instructions, dispatches, telegrams, histories, notes, questionnaires, statistical data, maps, charts, rosters, press summaries, printed matter, and other records of the New York office relating to Russian relief, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abbreviations (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 1
  - Agreements and executive orders (Riga, Fritjof Nansen, etc.) (Folder 2)
  - Agricultural pests (Folder 3)
  - Agriculture
    - General
      - 1921-1922 August 30 (Folder 4)
        Available on microfilm reel 2
      - 1922 August 30-1923 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 3
    - By districts (Folder 2)
      Available on microfilm reel 4
    - Crops
      - General
        - 1921 April 18-1922 August 31 (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 5
        - 1922 September 1-1923 October 30 (Box 3, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 6
      - Questionnaires. Returns by districts (Folder 2-3)
        Available on microfilm reel 7
    - Food supply, forage (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 8
    - Grain tax (Folder 2)
    - Grain trust (Klebo product) (Folder 3)
    - Seed grain (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 9
    - Ukraine (Folder 5)
  - Alcohol, Shipment of (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 10
  - American citizens (Folder 2)
  - American prisoners (Folder 3)
  - Appeals
    - General
      - 1921-1922 (Folder 4)
        Available on microfilm reel 11
      - 1923-1924 (Folder 5)
        Available on microfilm reel 12
    - Food remittances, clothing - Kazan, Samara (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 13
  - Appeals and letters of thanks (in Russian) (Folder 2)
  - A.R.A. Russian Museum (Folder 3)
    Available on microfilm reel 14
  - Anti-American propaganda (Folder 4)
  - Armenia (Folder 5)
  - Articles by Russian authorities (Folder 6)
  - Baltic Mission (Folder 7)
  - Berlin Conference, 1922 July (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 15
  - Bibliography (Folder 2)
  - Biographies (Folder 3)
  - Boy Scouts (Folder 4)
  - Bread
    - Analysis (Folder 5)
    - Loan (Folder 6)
  - British Commercial Mission (Folder 7)
  - Brussels Conference, 1921 October (Folder 8)
  - Cats (Folder 9)
  - Caucasus (Folder 10)
  - Children (Folder 11)
  - Childs, J. Rives, "Red Days in Russia" (Folder 12)
  - Church
    - General (Folder 13)
    - Treasure (Folder 14)
  - Chronology of Russian relief (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 16
  - Claims (Folder 2)
  - Clothing (Folder 3)
  - Cod liver oil (Folder 4)
  - Communications (Folder 5)
  - Containers (Folder 6)
  - Corn
    - General (Folder 7)
    - For railroad employees (Folder 8)
  - Cost of living (Folder 9)
  - Crime (Folder 10)
  - Crimea (Box 9)
    - General (Folder 1-2)
      Available on microfilm reel 17
    - Gold project (Folder 3)
    - History (P. J. Kohl and E. E. Fox) (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 18
    - Reports (Box 10)
      - General (Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 19
      - Economic and political (Folder 2)
      - Medical (Folder 3)
    - Warehouses, damaged cargoes (Folder 4)
  - Diseases (Folder 5)
    Available on microfilm reel 20
  - Economic bulletins (Folder 6)
  - Economic conditions, 1921-1923 (Folder 7)
  - Education (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 21
  - European Relief Council (Folder 2)
  - Exports and imports (Folder 3)
  - Famine
    - Data on previous famines (Folder 4)
    - 1921 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 22
    - 1922 (Folder 2)
  - Feeding
    - Adults (Folder 3)
      Available on microfilm reel 22A
    - Inspection (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 23
    - Points of feeding at peak of relief (Folder 2)
    - Progress
      - General (Folder 3)
      - By districts (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
        Available on microfilm reels 24 and 25
    - Results (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 25
    - Selection (Folder 2)
    - Tables (Folder 3)
  - Finance
    - General (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 26
    - Exchange rates (Folder 5)
    - Funds (Folder 6)
    - Soviet contributions to A.R.A. (Box 16)
      - General (Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 27
      - Russian supporting documents to Brooks Report (Folder 2-3)
      - Russian supporting documents to Brooks Report (Box 17, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 28
    - Weefer report on cost of foreign relief to Soviet government (Folder 2)
  - Finnish subjects (Folder 3)
  - Fire losses (Folder 4)
  - Food
    - Prices (Folder 5)
    - Shipments (Folder 6)
    - Substitutes (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Values (Folder 2)
  - Foreign affairs (Folder 3)
  - Foreign policy (Folder 4)
  - France, Joseph I. (Folder 5)
  - Geneva Conference, 1921 August 15-16 (Folder 6)
    Available on microfilm reel 29
  - Georgia (Folder 7)
  - Gifts (Folder 8)
  - Girl Scouts (Folder 9)
  - Gomel
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Allocation recommended (Folder 11)
    - Child feeding (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with local government representatives, organizations, and individuals (Folder 13)
    - Finance (Folder 14)
    - Food remittances (Folder 15)
    - History (J. I. Maitland), 1923 January 17 (Folder 16)
    - Medical supplies (Folder 17)
  - Gorky, Maksim (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Government
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Cooperation (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with local government representation and Gubispolkom (Folder 4)
    - Officials (Folder 5)
    - Relations
      - General
        - 1921 July-1922 June (Folder 6)
          Available on microfilm reel 30
        - 1922 (Folder 7)
        - 1922 July 1-1923 July 10 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - With districts (Folder 2)
        Available on microfilm reel 31
      - With districts (Box 21, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 31A
    - Special incidents (Folder 2)
  - Grain exports (Folder 3)
  - Haskell, William N. (Folder 4)
    Available on microfilm reel 32
  - Health (Folder 5)
  - Historical Department
    - Undated and 1921-1923 (Folder 6)
    - 1923 (Folder 7)
  - History
    - General
      - #1 (1. Outline of procedure; 2. Outline of government agreement; 3. Lists of supplies of advance party and main body) (Folder 8)
      - #2 (1-7. Organization charts; 8. Personnel) (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - #3 (1. Preliminary program; 2. Supplementary preliminary program; 3. Map of population density; 4. Map of waterways; 5. Map of railways) (Folder 2)
    - Harding, Warren - Letter (Folder 3)
    - Nansen, Fritjof, 1919 (Folder 4)
    - Negotiations
      - General
        - 1919-1921 (Folder 5)
        - 1921-1923 (Folder 6)
      - Fisher's summary (Folder 7)
    - "Skeleton History of the A.R.A. in Russia" (Folder 8)
  - History and policy
    - 1921 (Folder 9)
      Available on microfilm reel 33
    - 1921-1922 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 1922 January-May (Folder 2)
  - Industrial conditions (Folder 3)
    Available on microfilm reel 34
  - Industries (Folder 4)
  - Insurance
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Personnel policy (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Intelligentsia
    - General
      - 1921 (Folder 2)
      - 1922 (Folder 3-4)
        Available on microfilm reel 35
      - 1923 (Box 25, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 36
    - Bingham gift, 1923 (Folder 2)
    - Bishop Brent gift (Folder 3)
    - Donations from Commwealth Fund, 1920 June 22 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 37
    - Secondary teachers (Folder 2)
  - Karelia (Folder 3)
  - Kazan
    - General (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 38
    - Adult feeding - Corn (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Allocation recommended (Folder 2)
    - Child feeding (Folder 3)
    - Children's homes (Folder 4)
    - Chuvash district (Folder 5)
    - Clothing (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with government representatives (Folder 7)
      Available on microfilm reel 39
    - Finance
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Turner Report (Folder 9)
    - Food remittances (Folder 10)
    - Government contribution (Folder 11)
    - History
      - 1922 (Folder 12)
      - 1922 September-1923 June (Folder 13)
      - 1922 September-1923 June (Box 28, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 40
    - Instructions to A.R.A. Committee (Folder 2)
    - Intelligentsia (Folder 3)
    - Liquidation (Folder 4)
    - Livestock (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Mahri District (Folder 2)
    - Medical reports and supplies (Folder 3)
    - Medical supplies - Accounting (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 41
    - Memoranda (Folder 5)
    - Reports
      - General (Folder 6)
      - General (Box 30, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 42
      - Childs, J. Rives (Folder 2)
      - Turner (Folder 3)
    - Sarapol incident (Folder 4)
    - Seed grain (Folder 5)
    - Transportation (Folder 6)
    - Viatka (Folder 7)
  - Koslov (Folder 8)
  - Labor (Folder 9)
    Available on microfilm reel 43
  - Land holdings (Folder 10)
  - Laws and statutes (Folder 11)
  - Legislation (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 44
  - Liquidation
    - General (Folder 2)
      Available on microfilm reel 45
    - Agreement (Folder 3)
    - Letters from Russian staff (Folder 4)
    - Litvinov, Maksim. See H. H. Fisher's book for references
    - Protection (Folder 5)
  - Livestock (Folder 6)
  - Maps (Box 32)
    - General (Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 46
    - A.R.A. feeding maps and charts, general and district maps (Folder 2)
    - Crop conditions, general, medical, refugee movement, transportation, and communications (Folder 3)
  - Milk
    - General (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 47
    - Tins (Folder 5)
  - Minsk
    - General (Folder 6-7)
    - Beshenovitch (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Clothing
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Remittances (Folder 3)
    - Food remittances (Folder 4)
    - History (C. M. Willoughby), 1922 January 8-1923 June 15 (Folder 5)
    - Refugees - Soup kitchens (Folder 6)
    - Reports
      - General (Folder 7-9)
        Available on microfilm reel 48
      - Medical (Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 34)
    - 1917, 1922 (Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 49
    - 1922-1923 (Folder 2)
  - Moscow district
    - General (Folder 3)
      Available on microfilm reel 50
    - Collecting stations (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with government
      - Undated and, 1921 January-1922 July (Folder 2)
      - 1922 July-1923 (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 51
    - History (Donald Renshaw), 1922 July 26 (Folder 4)
    - Reports (Box 36)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Medical (Folder 2)
    - Students
      - Feeding (Folder 3)
      - "Student Relief in Moscow, " (by E. Bredin), 1922-1923 (Folder 4)
  - Moscow headquarters
    - Administrative Division
      - General (Folder 5)
      - History (E. G. Sabine) (Folder 6)
      - Memorandum (Folder 7)
    - Circular letters, (1-195, incomplete), 1921 October 27-1923 June 18 (Folder 8)
      Available on microfilm reel 52
    - Clothing Remittance Division (Box 37)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - A.R.A. bulletins (Folder 2)
      - Agreement (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 53
      - Application forms (in English, Russian, Yiddish) (Folder 4)
      - Child relief (Folder 5)
      - Correspondence
        - With districts, miscellaneous (Folder 6)
        - With government (Folder 7)
      - Patterns and cutting (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Reports (Folder 2)
      - Sales
        - General (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 54
        - Daily report (Folder 4)
    - Communications Division (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with districts, Miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Finance and Accounting Division
      - General, undated and, 1921 September 16-1923 September 8 (Folder 2)
        Available on microfilm reel 55
      - History (C. Telford) (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Memoranda (unnumbered and 1-15) (Folder 2)
    - Food Remittance Division
      - General
        - Undated and 1921 (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 56
        - 1922 January, May (Folder 4)
        - 1922 June, December-1923 (Box 41, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 57
      - Baltic Mission Report (Folder 2)
      - Bulk sales (Folder 3)
      - Competitors (Folder 4)
      - Complaints (Box 42, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 58
      - Continuation (Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with government (Folder 3-4)
      - Correspondence with government (Box 43, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 59
      - Danzig office (Folder 2)
      - Deliveries by districts
        - General (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 60
        - Weekly reports, 1921 November 12-1922 August 31 (Folder 4)
      - Forms (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - General relief (Folder 2)
      - Inquiries (Folder 3)
      - List of beneficiaries for more than $50 (Folder 4)
      - Loniao Bank, Constantinople (Folder 5)
      - Market value of food package (Folder 6)
      - Memoranda, circular letters, etc. (Box 45, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 61
      - Personnel (Folder 2)
      - Postal agreement (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 62
      - Publicity (Folder 4)
      - Sales (Box 46)
        - General (Folder 1)
        - Daily report (Folder 2)
          Available on microfilm reel 63
        - Eurelcon (Folder 3)
        - Geographical report, 1921 October 26-1922 July 29 (Folder 4)
        - Local (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Statistics
        - 1922 (Folder 2)
        - 1923 (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 64
      - Substitute packages (Folder 4)
      - Telegraph communications (Folder 5)
      - Tolstoi Committee (Folder 6)
    - Historical Division (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Inspection and Control Division
      - General (Folder 2)
      - "Consolidated Report of Relief Activities,", 1922 November 15-1923 May 31 (Folder 3)
      - History (P. S. Baldwin), 1923 July (Folder 4)
      - Memoranda (1-9) (Folder 5)
    - Liaison Division
      - General, 1921 August 25-1923 June 6 (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 65
      - Correspondence (Box 49)
        - General
          - A-E (Folder 1)
          - F-L (Folder 2)
            Available on microfilm reel 66
          - M-R (Box 50, Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 67
          - S-Z (Folder 2)
        - All districts, New York and London (Box 51, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 68
        - American Commissioner and Minister at Riga (Folder 2)
        - American Consul at Riga
          - General (Folder 3)
          - American passports (Folder 4)
          - Refunds to persons deported from the U.S. (Folder 5)
        - Soviet government (Folder 6)
      - History (Box 52)
        - Coolidge, A. C., 1921 September-1922 February (Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 69